welcome to the stoah the stoah is a
digital campfire where equal hear and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now okay
I'm recording we're here we're good
y'all can hear me welcome to the stoah
the stoah is a digital campfire where we
gather and Co here at the knife's edge
of this moment and I am looking forward
to this session this experience today
this is the second session of a series
called sensing the new myth that I am
facilitating and I've invited a friend
Duncan and we're going to be exploring
power and alpha dome and how we relate
to those with wisdom in this emerging
world and the way in which they touch
money and sex and relationships and
energetics and Duncan has an interesting
and unique life experience and Story
series of experiences that all seem
maybe very different from one another
but very interconnected and relating to
each other that has through our
conversations and my experiences of him
made me continually curious to learn
more about him to the point where I was
excited to invite him here to the stoah
and to bring this conversation here to
invoke in us deeper questions and
dialogue around power and how we can be
in right relationship with that so
before we get into it I would love to
hear quick from just a couple voices in
the room about what has brought you here
to this we space based on what you've
read about this session just real quick
expression maybe 30 seconds or so what
has brought you here so if anybody would
like to speak I would just love to see a
physical hand raised and I'll call on
somebody
who will volunteer rain I would love to
hear from you yeah I'm here because it's
a juicy topic and I'm curious about the
term alpha dumb and and kind of how you
define that and how that connects to
these other pieces and looking forward
to discussion from this awesome thank
you how about one other person okay
rheya I'm gonna unmute yeah I personally
have experienced Duncan and some
freestyle ciphers and really just
respect him as an artist and a creator
and so I'm just I'm curious about him
I'm curious all this conversation and I
when he speaks he has my attention so I
am just like um I'm here for it and I'm
excited cool thank you all right so with
that said Duncan I would love for you to
start by just introducing us to a little
bit about your story and where you're
approaching this conversation from and
I'll also add that at the end of the
hour so at 9:30 Eastern will conclude
the formal session and going to a
30-minute sense-making practice with
breakout rooms to continue the
conversation so I would love for y'all
to stick around for that if you can okay
know that yeah Duncan I would love to
just hear from you where are you
approaching this conversation about
power from so a little bit about your
personal story and then how that has
informed your explorations and questions
and perspective on alpha dome absolutely
and thank you for having me I really
appreciate and respect the stoah a lot
all of the speakers that I've seen have
been very very very high
signal-to-noise ratios and I hope not to
disappoint here so and thanks for
opening up and allowing me to indulge
hopefully not too much in my personal
background because I think it would be a
mistake to look at power the will to
accumulate power and to enact in the
world without looking at individuals
personal stories and motivations for
growing in strength power capabilities
usually each individual that I've seen
who has accumulated significant power
who has had the desire to do so has had
certain impacts in their own life that
have prefigured that search and my story
is no exception
very very brief overview of deep
childhood I was the first child first
grandchild in accelerated classes very
smart but very nerdy got picked on a lot
in school and then systematically
rebuilt myself after a lot of really
deliberate taunting and hazing over a
few years to become a class president
captain of various teams star in
different plays really redirected my
intelligence from quite literally in a
ritual one night at eleven from the
pursuit of goodness and knowledge to the
pursuit of power and the pursuit of
strength it was like a mirror ritual
that I later checked and you know had
some similarities to stuff that I had
figured out in like Western magic books
it was like these these strange echoes
occur at key junctures throughout my
life and I don't need to get too into
the weeds here suffice to say that from
11 to 13 I wrote a 13 page guide to
personality assimilation selected out
for seven key traits that I saw as
people who commanded influence and
respect and then modeled those to like
win a variety of accolades and awards
through my peers that was not a
sustainable personality structure
because it was built on raising like my
personality rank from like what I saw is
second least popular in my elementary
school to number six out of 520 in my
middle school and
I did get like that granular into the
specifics like I was that hazed in
school that it was that important for me
to figure out how to how to network and
how to understand these dynamics that I
was so sorely lacking in at the age of
like 10 but it fell apart because it
wasn't really based on a deeply embodied
sense of interconnection and like
authentic presentation and that was
coupled with my first mushroom trip at
21 and that triggered a real coming to
reality a really deep facing of the
nature of my existence and it triggered
both a spiritual awakening and a
profound breakdown where I spent six
months and then a year away from school
rebuilding myself and reintegrating the
sudden emergence of energies coursing
through my body
a sudden capacity to move my body in
different ways and do yoga and get all
of these these different insights that
my hyper cognitive brain didn't compute
or didn't have the background for before
and I had a faced a choice basically at
that point like in order to get
reintegrated into the world I could
either stay on different dumbing-down
medications or I could pursue yoga
meditation spirituality a clean diet and
various practices which would allow me
to maintain the various flows that I was
now experiencing in my reality after
that false personality that I
constructed had broken through so I
eventually found a variety of different
paths from karma yoga to Catholic Mass
to Gnostic groups in Brooklyn to Zen
Buddhism and eventually assumed to be
ex-girlfriend directed me down a path of
Tantra now I'm not talking about neo
Tantra sexual interplay although those
techniques have their their purpose and
their place it's more the
interpenetration of energies and
maximization of your capacity to sense
and expand perception and this was
necessary for me because my perception
was wildly fluctuating up
expanding the the images in my field
were so wild that I needed to take power
over that flux and so I ended up living
in China for a year
practicing various Taoist techniques and
then at the invitation of a friend going
down to Indonesia to take part in a
Tantra Kula that I would participate in
for the next two and a half years
learning how to Center my energy within
myself flow energy and send and receive
it to others and generally focus my
perception and capacity for sense-making
tracking facts deep communication with
power and understanding more about the
power of the world and how to and the
word and how to move my energy in order
to have effects on others and and this
was largely due to the instability that
I experienced in my early 20s was I was
willing to put a lot of energy into this
to smooth out these these gyrations
within my mind so a year and a half into
that I ran out of money I was working
for free on a dairy farm in central
North Carolina I was chanting every
morning to the cows Hanuman Chalisa and
various Sanskrit chants and I was
writing assiduously on alchemy and
Western philosophy and different
Sanskrit texts and trying to build a
synthesis within my mind to explain some
of these enhanced energetic states that
I had within this very high demand
spiritual group that I was still a part
of abroad via an internet forum where we
were all staying in close connection
through that forum i chance to meet
across the senior analyst in a New York
hedge fund who saw my writing asked how
long have you been pursuing this and I
was like well a month he was like what
if you picked up a financial report like
what kind of connections could you find
there's like well I've played poker I've
read The Economist once or twice why
don't you bring me on as an intern this
was seriously I was about to run out of
money
my mother was sending me money to
purchase prerequisite tests books for
nursing school at the age of 27
I really had not had much figured out
and was going all-in through this
pursuit of yoga meditation and Tantra on
on some kind of an uber mensch program
some kind of capacity to move and to
bend reality to in part make up for some
of the deficiencies in my background my
planning my capacity to move it anyway
he said the last person they brought on
was six years ago and it was him you
know tough luck but thank you for asking
but then two months later he gets a
promotion to the head of Asia trading
his wife who was really deep in this
organization says well why don't you
bring on Duncan and they both share a
laugh and they're like wait a second
what about that guy he'd at least be
really grateful so long story short in
the middle of a ritual that I was having
to clear myself out and to open myself
to whatever the universe had for me
within five minutes of the completion of
that I get an email in my inbox with the
internship offer at this like super
white shoe financial firm that routinely
turns away Stanford MBAs no background
no prerequisites haven't even handed in
a resume but I'm starting to do calls to
Brazil scouting stocks out there doing a
p90x workout routine and milking cows
and attending nursing school for anatomy
and physiology and that's my entire life
fast-forward six months I'm going to
Miami meeting a Brazilian CEO for a
potential deal and then flying back out
to Indonesia where everything hits the
fan I get intestinal parasites my whole
body breaks down I have to leave the
Tantra group lose 40 pounds I'm like go
down to 6-foot 135 pounds and then the
only tether in my life if his finance so
for the next six years I assiduously
pursue finance with all of the energetic
openness and flow that I've learned from
spiritual awakening and two and a half
years in a really intense Tantra Kula
with a lot of energies flowing through
so I learned how to open myself up to
interact with CEOs with billionaires
with people in very intense high power
high signal and high noise
professions and make sense of that and
try to understand that which undergirds
this reality I live in Boulder for two
and a half years recovering from my
illness and from a lot of the really
intense and somewhat manipulative
energetic games within that Tantra group
and then get a promotion to full analyst
with the firm and move to New York to
pursue that over the last few years
through my experiences in New York as
well I learned how to not only analyze
companies and see macro trends but I
experienced having personal power for
the first time I became a self-made
millionaire I gained the ability to
fulfill my own desires to a level that I
had never dreamed of when in 2014 I was
penniless working on a dairy farm for
room and board and getting in occasional
fights with the Baptist farmer who was
running the place so this is this is a
very day and night experience but I was
still somewhat emotionally traumatized I
still had yet to fully integrate my
bisexuality and feelings of inferiority
from that and I had not really rebuilt
the capacity to really hold deep and
lasting relationships in a New York
dating scene that veers far far more
towards polyamory as the status quo in
all but name only so it's an interesting
hybrid when somebody without the
credentials or capacity to even date or
form these bonds gets a lot of power
opens up into that field and learns with
a huge amount of energetic upsurge to to
grow there that's definitely one of the
things that I have learned through
experience how to actually hold and
honor other people in these kind of
fields but also with the caveat that a
lot of the power and capacity that I had
gained in Indonesia and through practice
had a visceral effect on others around
me especially powered up through finance
the energy of that money and the hyper
masculinization after the hyper-feminine
ization of year
and years of spiritual practice
I had fused in a kind of alchemical
marriage within me this had a narcotic
effect on certain people in my field who
were open to it and that presents a
power differential that I did not fully
understand was operating on myself and
on others in my field there are many
different kinds of power differentials
that I now realize and navigate you know
beyond the topical ones of white male
high rational IQ and capacity with the
background that I had to enter into a
white collar top-tier literally
polishing the eye on the pyramid kind of
job with no resume no questions asked
just looking as I do and with the
ability to with the ability to talk the
talk the talk and and learn that
language and and and beyond that as well
is the the capacity like knowing what
these energetic flows are and what world
capitalism is and also having
experienced pure powerlessness
so having experienced the capacity to
churn and work on the highest ideals but
having no capacity to network them or
put them into practice so going into it
with very high ideas and then learning
that the people that I was surrounded
with weren't really motivated by the
same things that I was motivated by that
in order to get ahead people cared about
financial results more than anything and
that the tech companies that I was
investing in and making the firm making
the firm money were actually getting
people in these reduced and reduced and
reduced systems of mind control of
abject simplification of the
complexities of thought that are
necessary to actually even conceive of
different systems let alone the shelling
points to putting them into practice I
realized that over the years that I was
in finance and I realized that a lot of
the connections that I was making were
fairly superficial
and motivated not by the quality of my
ideas but by connection to power so that
had a group effect on my field it almost
felt like the trace amounts of cocaine
that are on every hundred dollar bill in
long circulation so regardless of all of
that I I stepped down from Finance
gradually and stepped away from it and
found myself more drawn to poetry to
spoken word communication and to and to
group holding and community building and
and found that the energies and the
yogic states had a capacity to move
through spoken word and freestyle
vectors of communication and so I
learned how to pedal down and transition
and actually take stock on how
self-obsessed that I had been through a
lot of my life and how how self-involved
a lot of these processes were and how
informed by trauma a lot of them
actually were and how the effects on
other people and also the histories of a
lot of people in the fields that I was
in were impressed by their own childhood
trauma as well that drew a lot of people
to grow to states of power that they
wouldn't otherwise have have gotten to
so a lot of a lot of that backstory you
know I'm not covering it up and I'm
definitely willing to expand and explore
and express in any vector that anybody
would be interested in exploring and
experiencing we live in an era where it
can be quite damaging and difficult to
tell the truth and to experience things
directly we live in an era where like
people have a lot of very strong
feelings about you know every everybody
who is trying to attain a level of power
and a level of influence and a level of
visibility
and I've had to reckon and continue to
reckon with my own and I've made many
mistakes in relating to others in
leveraging the power imbalances that I
felt but I've also learned a lot through
holding them and just want to tip my
hand you know I've played a lot of Poker
I want to play my cards as face-up as I
possibly can because that's not the game
that I want to play and this is more
than signaling and it's really important
to me that I express that because this
world is not in a great state and I
don't know the answers but I know that
higher higher signal and less noise and
like more actual truth and more deep
emotions from people who have the chance
to do things and and more vulnerability
is where people people like me and
people without convoluted histories and
backstories can actually learn how to
serve other people and how to serve a
collective so with that I'd like to open
it back up to you Tyson and thank you
again for having me here great Thank You
Duncan so I'm gonna ask a question if
anyone has any questions coming up or on
the node of like Duncan and poking you
know we have many of us have strong
feelings about some of these things
power dynamics and things like finance
and on Wall Street or spiritual
practices and communities like Duncan's
experience with Tantra things like this
feel free to just put in the comments
like any strong feelings opinions
anything about this that points to
anything that has challenged you that
you're thinking about even if it's just
a comment not necessarily a question
just put it in the chat and let that
sort of anything that might bubble up
come up because this will kind of feed
the dialogue that we go into at the end
of this and one thing I'm curious about
Duncan is you know having spent time in
different spiritual communities and
tribes there is definitely and I think
many times it's rightly rightfully but a
a major resent
demonization towards finance Wall Street
and people that hold power which I
totally get I'm curious what lessons did
you learn being in the world of Wall
Street and in finance and having that
experience that that maybe those in the
spiritual community that just turn away
from it and dislike it that there could
be they could be missing out on what
wisdom is there and then also I guess in
connection with that is like what do
people get wrong in general and your
experience about Wall Street finance and
people with power in those realms okay
so first off I was lucky to be in the
firm that I was in you know it was less
Gordon Gekko than grad school it was it
was somewhat somewhat nerdy somewhat
self-involved within like a narrow
parameter and way of seeing the world
but the head of the firm had a very
strong commitment at least in his
worldview to truth and to basically to
sense-making
to to market behavior as since making
and to updating his reality and learning
as much as possible and that's what
you'll see
we were we were long-term value
investors so we weren't short-term
trying to profit off of market movements
or day traders or that level of gambling
we never worked off of insider
information but we did all that was
legally possible to visit companies tour
entire industries talk to as many former
employees as possible about
non-confidential topics but it was a lot
like doing homework and the work that I
was asked to do and that all the
analysts were asked to do is seven three
grade math it's not very complicated
don't have to put it up on a pedestal
whatsoever but that coupled with a lot
of reporting due diligence reporting and
essay writing so I would I would take
calls and just
that into core information about a
certain company or a certain industry
talk to all the competitors compare it
with like global comps and use that to
gain an information advantage on what
the what the markets are currently
saying you know the the the funnest part
of my job was VC investing because then
you get to be a part of something that
might not otherwise exist in the world
that had a lot more life in it and more
impressive personalities but like any
competitive game you want to be in the
places with fewer players or you want to
be in the places where there's more
uncertainty so I specialized in Brazil
India China you know the the the BRIC
companies were where countries were
where we had the most advantage and
where somebody without a lot of
background in the industry could come
and make a lot of contacts very quickly
Brazil was in particular great for me
because there's such an open people it's
kind of a telenovela everybody loves to
gossip and make friends and so the more
information and the more connections you
can get the more access to opportunity
or as warren buffett puts it deal flow
you're given so a lot of it was based on
reputation we were a large firm so we
had the potential to alter people's
lives with the money that we could move
and so people were more forthcoming to
talk to us smaller firms don't get that
kind of access now the head of the firm
is an interesting character I'm not
going to talk to about him that much
because he prefers to remain private
but very he puts his money in the right
place you know he basically tie this to
environmental charities that he hand
picks that are like running themselves
like businesses or running the world
like a renewable sustainable business so
at least in his mind he's fairly
sensitive open and though he crunches
probably 300 pages of information per
day he makes his decisions based on his
subconscious based on into it
needs to keep that channel clear and the
job of the you know dozen or so people
who work for him is to order that
information in a way that he could end
up making the proper decision that the
information is clear signal and accurate
that it is broad and widely resourced
and that it allows his intuition to make
the right choice because at the end of
the day you can argue that the mind
doesn't actually make decisions it just
presents different outcomes in different
different weights and that the will to
make a choice comes from somewhere
different I will say structure power
structure of it it was more feudalism
the full analysts were kind of like
Knights going off into different sectors
or territory claiming land and the
industry is compensated from the
top-down released our firm was so
meritocracy was filtered through the
leading personality the portfolio
manager who made the decisions on
allocation and made all of the decisions
on compensation himself so that has its
own problematic tendencies of
potentially creating a cascade of
sycophantic behavior which every analyst
would have to weigh within their
decision-making process not to
brown-nose somebody who has ultimate
power on how much abundance you're how
much of that group energy you're going
to be sharing in but it's it's a large
pool few analysts so you you get to
experience experience that so I am
there's some interesting questions in
the chat here as follow-ups yeah there
are and I'm so I'm personally curious
about bringing this in to sex
relationships energetics and I think
Ariel's question is interesting as well
so I would like to call on Arielle to
ask her question and we'll go to engine
afterward
hey yeah this is all super fascinating I
just be really curious to hear more like
specifics about how those polarities you
were discussing being married within
yourself like a feminine spiritual and
the money power masculine uh like
impacted love and dating absolutely well
it's there there's a couple of things
involved here and I I'll say first off I
was learning as much as I could to
expand myself to hold the energy of
Finance
it was jarring to my system coming from
no money and then being with these like
really directed personalities some of
them with more capacity to hold
attention than most of the monks that I
had met like very very centered balanced
equanimous focused on their goal and
with really systemic lives so their
energy was moving through my spine and I
received them similarly to a Tantra guru
like it was just a different kind of
energy moving through my system now that
was coupled with like the receptivity
that I'd experienced in in finance and I
was still drawn to two women and when
men but mostly women with really open
systems with really direct system so
like dating dating was interesting you
know for the first couple of years in
finance I was really recovering from
illness and from the intense
psychological impact of a lot of the
practices that I'd experienced in Tantra
and abroad I I didn't do much dating
when I lived in Boulder when I lived in
New York it opened up a lot and a lot of
avenues but largely through the ecstatic
dance scene so I didn't really date in
the finance sphere it was a bit closed
to me a lot of it is married to upper
crust New York
and it was also a little bit foreign to
my nervous system so working in finance
there was a lot of tension moving
through my system and I longed to have
like really open experiences and flow it
it felt like a double life and I felt
like a double agent and I wanted to
understand finance from the inside and
make shifts but I wanted to date women
who is serious about deepening into yoga
caring about the world caring about
energy and life and that was what I was
drawn to in my personal life and I found
that it was an interesting a really
interesting feel just like having never
really had a lot of attractions to me
beforehand in my life and being insecure
about my own mental state or being
insecure about where money was going to
come from I remember selling a poem for
food like when I was 22 or 23 because I
was just like that short up to being
able to treat anybody to whatever meals
or whatever experiences and just not
more important than that was not having
any anxiety in my body the shift to
having a fully relaxed like root system
and having the lower tiers of Maslow's
hierarchy of needs shored up created
just a real phase shift so it was I was
finally experiencing this kind of magic
and physical magic but my heart wasn't
fully open to it and part of that heart
not being open was also I didn't fully
believe in what I was doing in finance
and I wasn't finding people to date or I
wasn't in the right state and it was a
combination thereof like when I lived in
Boulder there would be regular energetic
transmissions on the energy to energy
level and when I moved to New York I
found that being sexualized just so very
quickly
it was quite jarring for me at first how
people would like experience this energy
escalate physically and it took about
six months to to really experience and
live in that scene without being jarred
but I would say I wish I had the
fortitude to choose more long-distance
relationships and to choose more
commitments because a lot of the dating
was just for a month or just for a
couple of weeks until my emotional
traumas were triggered and then I would
find some regular pretext that it would
that it would blow up or not work or
prime people not to make commitments
because I had to fly to China or I had
to go here or I had to do this in that
it it was difficult to going back into
into work and toughening up because I
experienced it almost like a corset
being fastened on my chest and my
abdomen going into work so I would
deliberately go to ecstatic dances and
to like these really more open groups to
just like re release the tension that
had built up during the day that I was
literally taking on from my peers my
boss loved me and I remember an acid
trip and the Metropolitan Museum of Art
very shortly after joining the firm in
New York I left and I looked down the
avenue of poets in Central Park and
looked at this building this is where
Moloch really comes in to the question
in the chat I saw it rising like the
monolith from the Planet of the Apes
from the from Cleopatra's Needle or
whatever the the obelisk is in Central
Park and I saw like the four hundred
Lions from the top of the building where
I work just like moving out and
connecting to these wealthy families all
over the world that we were serving and
I heard like it literally felt like a
voice like this was raw
speaking to me like it was saying you
are here to serve these these wealthy
chosen and then if you do successfully
your children will be among their number
and I remember just like taking that
trip and just like walking
twelve miles back to Brooklyn not saying
yes not saying no previously I'd been in
the museum was just like seeing all the
funerary masks of the Dead Kings and
being like this is the afterlife that
they were looking for but there was one
piece that most resonated in my psyche
which was this African King with a great
golden staff to the side and that staff
was for his chief adviser who was there
to clean and clear the energy from the
King so that he could make worthy
decisions and I looked at it was like
fuck that's me that's that's my primary
job here I'm gonna find some good
investments I'm gonna find some bad
investments but I'm here to clean the
energy and you know when I moved from
Boulder to New York I saw myself as this
living crystal on the grid line of
Manhattan trying to help clear and reset
the energy there and it was it was a big
task and people from Boulder were like
good luck and I I don't know how
effective that I was when I was there
and I know that I've moved on from from
dating and I'm talking about some of
these energetic dynamics I hope it's not
too off course Tyson
no thank you Ariel do you have any
follow-up question cool engine I would
love to hear from you whatever a
question is most alive at this point
sorry for spamming the chat I've waited
so long to talk to somebody who's like
on the inside of Finance and Wall Street
and I feel like like so much thought is
spent thinking about how could we craft
a different world this rent-seeking
Moloch that comes out of Finance of Wall
Street and said have somebody who's been
in the sausage factory even though it
seems like your experiences a little
different than the most is just
incredible I don't know which of the
questions I asked to pick so you'd like
to pick the the Moloch question is maybe
yeah
yeah the the Moloch and the economic
system we need to overcome the wealth
inequality or is Maalik first yeah
that's good maybe go to Moloch first and
then we'll move on to the question that
I don't know who originally asked it but
now Margaret is double-tap in it yeah so
Scott Scott Alexander's Moloch I've I've
read that and I'm quite familiar with
that and the holy crap the Allen
Ginsberg I have seen the best minds of
my generation crunching financial models
for to maximize alpha-2 to maximize this
above safe return or above market return
and what is capitalism but a conversion
of the world into capital it is quite
literally a deadening process that turns
living energy into the capacity for
potential energy at a future date you
know
Moloch is the love of money right it's
not money that's the root of all evil
it's the love of money that is the root
of all evil it's like the preferencing
of the the inert potential for change
rather than living it in the present
moment so it's quite literally a
projection outside of the present moment
by extrapolating on past data the only
decision that takes place in the present
moment is the decision to buy or sell so
that's almost the the kind of conceptual
consummation of the transaction is the
moment of transfer of ownership and
that's how it that's how it perpetuates
I know that's that's a little bit vague
and high-level or but Moloch Moloch in
that sense is acceleration because of
compound interest you know it's it's um
if if you view you you can you can go
into dualistic like Zoroastrian concepts
like adora Mazda the light bringer and
Ahriman like the tendency of of nature
to reduce back into matter you know or
the the descent with life itself like
the the terminus of like Naked
Capitalism is the conversion of
everything into capital into matter
which is quite quite dangerous and so it
always needs to be bounded
and when you're working there you can
actually see the tendency of that to
continue unbounded and the effects that
it has on people's psyche over time I
left about six to nine months after
getting warned by the two people I was
closest in if you stay in this this will
change you this will change you you know
is is it was repeated I don't mean to be
all doom and gloom about it though you
know I also want to codify that an
incredibly powerful engine for looking
at reality for understanding how value
is created for understanding how how
truth and facts can actually be matter
it measured and conveyed over time you
know a lot of these people stick to the
facts have a rather scientific and
disciplined way of noticing it and and
Warren Buffett also says you know you
only need you know 115 IQ to make it big
in this business 130 is enough for
everything beyond that it's
psychological stability over time you
know 90 99 percent of his wealth came
after the age of 50 due to the miracle
or the terror depending on the use you
put in a compound interest and he's
giving most of that money to charity is
it too late is that the right stuff ask
Bill Gates but the the jam there is he
will and ended up making a lot of
positive personal difference in the
world although the system of compound
interest I would argue that we don't
have time for it to work right now I
think that and that's one of the reasons
that I left in addition to feeling the
slippage of my own morals and not not
having my own fortitude to last in the
world as a double agent without feeling
my myself slide in my own traumas coming
to the surface and clouding my decisions
was I'm terrified that we don't actually
have time to compound and convert into
something new so that comes to what kind
of shift must happen for a new system to
take place like what kind of economic
system do we need to overcome today's
growing wealth inequality I mean there
there are a few things that are obvious
low-hanging fruits right you
personal healthcare is a must and
because the one of the folks one of the
focuses of government is to crack down
on undue monopolies monopolies of power
pay-to-play system systems where you
have to take place and the owners of
that system can charge whatever price
they want everyone has a monopoly over
their own health so anybody will be
incented to pay whatever price they have
and you see that what's Corelli and the
jacking up of pharmaceuticals companies
you see that all over all over the board
another thing is defending the Commons
so defending the ecological Commons like
government's actually must be able to do
that in order to ensure the health and
well-being of citizens otherwise these
governments are illegitimate same with
economic models the low-hanging fruit I
would say definitely a carbon cap and
trade system but is it even feasible in
two and four year governmental cycles
where climate and carbon legislation can
be wiped from the board within such a
short period of time and that years of
unilateral agreements can can be wiped
out with a single populist
administration I mean hopefully this is
a boil that we're bursting but you know
with the Poland's populist president was
was reelected like this may not go away
for for quite some time and do we have
the time to move through it then at the
far end of the spectrum I've heard of
technocratic systems of a global carbon
bank and and carbon allotment and energy
allotment that we require a world
government that so many on the far so
many on the far end near left and right
are afraid of because it too could be
manipulated by bad actors at the core or
goes flies in the face against people
like the Koch brothers who have built a
series of shell corporations to
successfully lobby their corporate
interests into the minds of one half of
the US and much of the world so
I'm sorry that my my answer isn't giving
more concrete information but I I I
think that the moral currency of the
system oh okay okay okay this is this is
actually a bit more productive right so
what what established the primacy of the
West
you could you could say that it is the
the corporate structure credit the
capacity to invest in things with a
long-term return so it's trust it's
trust in some kind of future scenario
and capacity to generate returns over
time right so that built into just the
weaponization and export of trust
systems into lower trust climates with
without that infrastructure so the Dutch
West Indies corporation and and the
British East India Company went and
exported colonization to polities that
hadn't developed this system of trust
they were so rich in natural resources
that they didn't need to build these
societal structures and so it was taken
from them used to bolster this system of
global inequality that impoverished the
global South that led to the exporting
of human capital into the south of
America to work plantations that led to
the unfair elevation of whites and
especially white males to dominate over
the global South and the echoes of that
to persist through history so one thing
that's really necessary is serious
capital formation among disadvantaged
groups and communities I do think some
degree of redistribution is an order but
also cultural shifts really against
redlining against systematic preference
thing of of white males in these
positions of power you know there was
one female analyst at my work all of all
of the other races represented were
Asian Indian in some way but it was
mostly white male
that was jarring to me and felt very
very brittle and overly constrained but
it's it is a honest representation of a
lot of the what goes for diversity over
the history of capital formation at
large it has yet to really change and it
needs to it absolutely needs to in order
for a true diversity of opinions come in
but that's still not changing the
underlying ecological framework there
needs to be a price on the extraction of
what we're taking from the planet in
order to to sustain this imbalance of
power and there hasn't been a price yet
and we're going to pay it in 50 to 60
years in a big way due to soil depletion
water depletion all of the above and
that's being researched and priced in
and you know the military knows it
certain mines and Finance know it
everybody knows and acknowledges it but
people are still playing the same the
same zero-sum game structure so how to
convert to an infinite game and positive
some games in a field where everyone is
in this prisoner's dilemma hell is
shelling point of defect defect how to
break the tit-for-tat and how to get
accept except when you know if you
become an ethical investor the other guy
is gonna take the profits from X
corporation or or Y I want to bounce
this out because we could spend the
whole call on this and this is the big
question that we're facing in this time
but I think just more more voices need
to be speaking this directly with
accountability and more fund managers
and more heads of state need to be
fucking saying this and speaking
directly regardless of the short-term
economic consequences or their
reelection chances or whatever donations
they can drum up from large donors that
actually perpetuates their capacity to
spam messages to whatever their
constituent base is that passes for
democracy and whatever this system
actually is because it is not a
democracy and I know that you know I've
seen politicians come in
out of high offices and meet with fund
managers I know that much
excuse me well with ten minutes
remaining or nine minutes in this first
part of the session and getting close to
where we'll go and continue this
dialogue the question that's coming up
for me now is so how shall we as a
community and just the people in this
room keep it personal how should we
relate to obtaining power or wielding
power or experiencing alpha'd um and
this might be something along the lines
of the question that we take out into
our breakout rooms in the dialogue and
so before going into a artistic
expression to wrap us up Duncan your
thoughts now on guiding us into our
inquiry of how is it that we wield power
with wisdom or do we do do we do that at
all
how do we play the game and whether you
have a better question or something that
points toward a direction for us to take
in our sense making practice yeah
absolutely we are we are living in
capitalism is a religious system with
the idol of money in golden golden idol
golden bowl to be specific we are living
in a system where idols are measured
based on how much money they're they're
pulling in you look at the the Sacred
Feminine of capitalism that'll be Kim
Kardashian you cannot read an article
about her without how much money her
Instagram posts are pulling in and how
you know her worth is based on
measurements a blank canvas for the
projection of whatever qualities you
want to put on and the money that she is
pulling in you you look to the other
side of the spectrum and I'm sorry to
highlight that you you you want to
highlight that you look at like the
idols of finance they are extra
hopefully and I'm fortunate I've
connected to a lot of people with an
earnest desire to give back and
that there are many many they're the
ones that make the news thus Corelli's
of the world are the ones that are the
Gerardi and scapegoats of modern society
they are the agreed upon evil that has
existed from all of society so that the
system can perpetuate itself and off-gas
inequality it's not just that it's the
the good actors who tithe to the
environment and to education and aren't
just like putting their names on
buildings as a proxy for the length of
their members but the the good actors
also need to examine themselves you have
to look at the primary source if the
money is coming from zero-sum games then
that's what we're idolizing as a society
Silicon Valley is little better in a lot
of ways you know the the platforms are
all becoming more extractive by the day
higher add load higher time you know
higher higher noise to signal ratio for
their own profits and the profits of
shareholders especially as the founders
transition out and professional
management trickles in you'll see that
in every single platform and the best of
them the people who can withstand this
compression and I will lionize Elon Musk
here he's actually creating shit he's
building new things and he's using the
new wealth that he gets to get more
credit to build more amazing things in a
race against time because he actually
gets the urgency of creating new worlds
and creating new solutions so we should
we should really be lionizing not the
people with the biggest bank accounts or
the capacity to build platforms that
capture public attention and then
monetize those platforms which is
extractive that's also rent-seeking you
know Facebook is incredibly rent-seeking
Google is incredibly rent-seeking wasn't
always but you know is is now but you
you you transitioned out the people who
are truly building solutions and it's a
reading right because it's a transition
back to not just the Roman culture but
the Greek culture that spawned it a
culture of team a and Gatos of Honor as
the current
see and Garros the the war prize the
blood prize what did you risk what did
you risk what are you going to fight for
what will you risk your reputation for
what will you fuckin fuckin burn beyond
the deadening qualities of nihilism
which is just the death throes of a
system collapsing on itself because it
is so narcissistic as a system that it
redefines everything is capital and can
only see the world as that and so its
death throes will be a systemic apathy
and nihilism in everybody who derives
their sense of Worth and being from that
system and yes it does go back seven
generations because that's what we're
seeing so it does actually take
epigenetic reconditioning it takes the
yoga and the meditation and it takes
doing it in fucking earnest and I
haven't always been there and there are
temptations that you that come when you
gain any level of power that's
significantly greater than your peers in
any field there isn't a manual for
abundance that is more than 2 Sigma
outside of the mean because it isn't
profitable to sell but that's what we
need as leaders we need manuals for 2
Sigma plus 4 twice and thrice
exceptional 's who would be so impacted
by the world that they could curl up in
narcissism or play power games as a way
to punish the world for their childhood
traumas and I know because I've played a
few of them and I want to call them out
and I want to stop them and myself and
and others who were very capable but
inflicted by these echoes or wounds or
inflicted by this systemic apathy which
again is just the system dying for
something new to be born so it's a it's
a renewed rekindling of personal
practice but not just sitting on your
thumb on a yoga mat connecting like this
and building new new games creating
something new celebrating each other for
that pushing people to craft that voice
that needs to be expressed that speaks
beyond the dead zone that I think is a
path to
Oshin that's why I left finance and I'm
working more in the creative arts and
trying to build a platform for others to
express themselves as well and it's it's
painful learning I you know I I faced my
own traumas any any leadership roles
require a lot but it's it's a start and
I'm very very open to feedback along the
way because we can't do this alone
nobody can I would like to do that's
yeah I want to bring this home with an
artistic expression and so if you're
ready and prepared for that Duncan then
absolutely that's what we'll get into
since we are two minutes from the hour
mark I will for anyone that might have
to go for any reason open the
opportunity Peter if you do want to
share any announcements or anything then
this would be a time I know there's an
event that um tomorrow as well as
another sensing the new myth with
Michael Meade who is a renowned
mythologist and storyteller and author
he'll be speaking on a personal genius
and how that relates to the collective
rite of passage and initiation where and
now so I'm really looking forward to
having him on he's wise elder and in my
life and yeah Peter anything at all yeah
so first uh thank you
Tyson Thank You Duncan for visiting
stoah it's greatly appreciated
definitely check out the sensing a new
myth event tomorrow with Tyson and
before that at 12 p.m. Eastern time we
have the meta-crisis of the meta-crisis
with johannes and leader Hauser and he's
gonna criticize this Jazzy term the meta
crisis so looking forward to that all
right well I really look forward to I've
got a few questions that are coming up
for our collective dialogue in our
breakout rooms before we get there I
don't know invited uncle too maybe
to weave this all together in a way that
expresses it better than any and that is
free-style poetics so I'm going to hit a
beat here and thunking in the form of
yours what's wrong and this time it
might be helpful to get real close to
your mic all right positive how's this
be for you
power is the wellspring of temptation if
you want to find a dream beyond the
false creation you've got to reach
inside yourself and go beyond the power
of the castle the heii and the slaves to
the vasa when the master speaks we all
see a guy and polish the reflection of
the oven I volunteer you can open it
wide if you can let your intuition you
spell it out wide and you reach to the
future that's the night as I speak let
it down for the triumphal fault now if
you want to understand the vow and let
it out hold on we got a crack crack
crackling now because the sound keeps
shifting but now anyhow because the
world keeps as we could speak our minds
you gotta open wide and let the truth
decide let it inside out
eighty thousand times cut off the leaves
with the way taken advantage of our in
my gut and I wanna make you a bride and
I think everybody gets the chance to
thank you right now for sharing this
light we must share our all eyes to
speak also bright and you know that is
true and I do not incite something
that's not in you speak it open it wide
you let it decide you let it decide
because that is you can spit facts you
can talk math but that won't take class
that won't move the masses like a hit of
acid you got to open wide and let it all
go pass it don't go so passive don't be
so creative you gotta open wide and let
that speak don't hate it fucking love
but love with a fire that is so damn
bright that you light up and banished
the Exile of this night of capital
Moloch sent to the gray of where he
belongs because he wasn't anything to
save you as an echo and a drama never
even real it's just the arc of matter to
refuse to feel leave that a few number
one numero uno get vulnerable get true
though and don't echo in Girardi and
sacrifice games boom-boom tit-for-tat
cuz that's more of the same you don't
have to shame and guard with the shame
yes bad actors are exiled but still
beyond tame is true and real power needs
to be yoked to the truth an engine that
moves beyond passion or proof in his
fire it is fire and let it all burn
these petrified woods to carbon to
return than sequestered bury it deep let
it spoil and spurn for we all are asleep
halfway
tired of voices that shout but we know
that there is something to shout about
and we grow stronger for every word of
truth that we speak so I'm not talking
about the flavor of the week thank you
[Music]
thank you for heating things up so we
can go and mix it all up so I would like
to surface a question and whatever
question is most alive to you in your
breakout room you can run with so in
this moment we can all meet yourself so
if there's just a question that anyone
wants to send us into the breakout rooms
with to explore together and then we'll
come back and have a collective dialogue
around it and what we explored yeah for
anyone that's got to go that's cool
thanks Camille and so let's see Duncan
is there any question for you that you
would like to send us into the breakout
rooms with mm-hmm a question from me for
the breakup rooms here yeah and then
we'll explore that together in our
individual conversations I would say
where where have you been discouraged
from creating value in your lives and
sharing it with others and given the
world that we live in
what are actionable steps that you can
create that value in in a way that can
move the world into a sustainable and
inspiring direction and I know that
that's not quite on the topic but that's
just what's what's burning in me I guess
the the distillation of that is how can
how can we transition from toxic
self-serving power to a sense of power
which empowers yourself and others how
can you sustainably unlock that within
yourself
to empower a different story and a
different vision within this world that
we all share yeah that's really good
thank you and I'm inspired
Duncan by you talking about your
experience and I'm just like billing
being willing to explore the times where
[Music]
you face like the temptations of power
and then how that reveals in me to think
about the moments where I have where I
have an even in small sort of contexts
and situations seeks to leverage my
personal power too for my own personal
gain even potentially at someone's
expense and so I think for me what is
happening here that is meaningful is to
when those experiences those moments
those temptations desires come up to
talk about it like to be open and honest
I'm experienced in this because I got my
own fantasies and desires and things
around power and feeling powerful that
are less virtuous and less healthy hmm
and so I do personally want to keep
myself with like beauty and truth and
goodness as a compass yeah but and so
yeah go ahead no that's that's that's
probably much more useful to bring into
the breakout rooms yes your questions
good and what I wanted to encourage was
everyone to take this as an opportunity
to talk about your personal experiences
with that with power when you had power
and when you used it in one way or
another in a way that felt good and
right or maybe a way that felt kind of
wrong and dirty and I think by allowing
ourselves to get personal with it that
will help us answer or at least create
ideas and and deeper questions around
Duncan's question
and and and that level of self
acknowledgement you're you're all beings
probability dictates that you're all
beings with moral compass and maybe one
of you has different neuro chemistry but
like so she sociopathy is where you
didn't that sense of consciousness are
in conscience
to the point where that feedback
mechanism doesn't take place and if you
feel ashamed of your use of power there
will be a subtle voice saying don't
accumulate power don't grow a powerful
but if you listen to that voice without
re-experiencing even like childhood
trauma of like I took the sugar when I
was three and so I'll never do anything
bad again or like take the sugar like
and you didn't that that limits your
capacity to enact and listen to that
voice and listen and actually grow
strong and virtuous but it actually does
take speaking about it to to make that
place open and real so if you feel that
trust it's so valuable especially as a
person of virtue to to acknowledge and
speak where your virtues have been
lacking and it's it's a journey for me
and it's an ongoing journey for me but
it's it's one that I'm really grateful
for thank you again
yeah great ok so if anybody has any
questions as I set these breakout rooms
okay can you come back I would love that
and then what would you suggest as the
the title or topic for the next session
epic rap battle Tyson versus Duncan zero
zero some rap battle or a positive some
rap battle yeah that's good I've been
thinking about that as the refrain for
rap battles where as freestyle and my
sessions on Monday as a opportunity for
argumentation healthy argumentation
rather than battling one another and
trying to tear each other down how do we
use freestyle to wrestle with one
another in our ideas that's been kind of
happening organically it flowing with
that knowingness on Mondays and Duncan I
would I would love to see you there
sometime